你还好吗?我只是心脏有问题。
Are you all right? I just have a heart condition.
如果你给我打电话，我就跑过来，即使我知道你不是真的感兴趣。
If you ring me, I'll run round here even though I know you're not really interested.
“我不是不感兴趣。”
'I'm not NOT interested.'
拉夫?“我想他已经明白了，知道了什么。”
Raff? 'I assume he's seen the light, worked out what'
你真是个疯婆子。如果他想搬来住，我没意见。
a mad bitch you are. If he wants to move in here, that's fine by me.
你竟敢向他灌输我的坏话。
Don't you dare fill his head with rubbish about me.
这段婚姻结束了，我不想再浪费另一段…愚蠢的母狗!
This marriage is over and I do not want to waste another... Silly bitch!
．.我花了这么多时间假装这是值得拯救的东西!
..second of my life pretending it's something worth saving!
他叹息着说
HE GROANS
他在这里做什么?他没有别的地方可去。
What's he doing here? He's got nowhere else to go.
你想要什么?你不能借给我一些钱，是吗?
What do you want? You couldn't lend me some money, could you?
你想在哪里结婚?你知道，现在你可以在任何地方结婚。
Where would you like to get wed? You can get wed anywhere now, you know.
喂?有人在吗?
Hello? Is anybody there?
哦,不!
Oh, no!
雷声隆隆，大雨倾盆
THUNDER RUMBLES RAIN POURS
现在都安全了。你为什么不回到暖和的地方去呢?
It's all safe now. Why don't you get back in t'warm?
我们要下车了。再见。谢谢。
We'll get off. Bye. Thanks.
雷声不断
THUNDER CONTINUES
“你好，我是艾伦·巴特肖。请在哔声后留言。”
'Hello, this is Alan Buttershaw. Please leave your message after the tone.'
哔哔的声音
BEEP
爸爸，是我……再说一遍，只是想说……
Dad, it's me...again, just to say...
她叹了口气
SHE SIGHS
…你在哪里，你收到我最后一条短信了吗，
...where are you, basically, and did you get my last message,
叫外卖吗?因为……
about picking up a takeaway? Cos...
发生了这么多事，我都没时间考虑做饭了。
I've not been able to think about cooking with all this going on.
她叹了口气
SHE SIGHS
再见。
Bye.
我真不想现在发生这种事。
I so didn't need this happening right now.
你得打电话给你的保险公司。
You'll have to ring your insurance.
他们会给我50英镑。
They'll give me about 50 quid for it.
我怎么能再买一个呢?
How the hell am I going to buy another one?
你可以用我的车。
You can use my car.
谢谢。
Thanks.
是怎么开始的?哦，他们不知道——闪电……电气故障……
How'd it start? Oh, they don't know - lightning...electrical fault...
你不会认为有人把它烧了吧?
You don't think someone torched it?
像谁?
Like who?
Cresswells。海莉愚蠢的兄弟们。
Cresswells. Hailey's stupid brothers.
我希望我爸爸能回家。
I wish me dad would get home.
他们应该一个多小时前就到了。
They should've been here over an hour since.
噢!
Ooh!
你知道吗，我的牌很烂。
D'you know, I've had some poor cards.
风呼啸着，门开了
WIND HOWLS DOOR OPENS
哦，她又来了。
Oh, there she goes again.
#用她的头…
# With her 'ead...
西莉亚加入:#…蜷缩在她的手臂下
CELIA JOINS IN: # ...tucked underneath her arm
她走在该死的塔上!＃
# She walks the bloody tower! #
我们在这里，亲爱的!
We're in here, love!
你说得对，这是一种抽风。
You're right, it'll be a draught.
这么大这么老的房子，如果不咯吱咯吱地响才怪呢。
House this size, this old, it'd be odd if it didn't creak and make a few noises.
打完这手，我们再去趟厕所好吗?
Shall we make another expedition to t'water closet after this hand?
嗯，没问题。
Mmm, can do.
我不知道接待处的电话为什么坏了。
I don't know why that telephone at reception won't work.
这显然是有联系的。
It's obviously connected.
我很惊讶我们居然没有拉响警报。
I'm amazed we've not set off an alarm.
你觉得有人发现我们失踪了吗?
D'you think anyone's realised that we're missing?
门打开
DOOR OPENS
约翰:她就在这儿，就在这儿，让我问问她。卡洛琳……
JOHN: She's just here, just now, let me ask her. Caroline...
这是怎么回事?爸爸的烹饪。
What's all this mess? Dad's cooking.
你考试考得怎么样?好的……伊什。
How was your exam? Good...ish.
回答一切吗?
Answered everything?
嗯。没有令人不快的惊喜吗?
Mmm. No nasty surprises?
卡洛琳，我是吉莉安。谁?
Caroline, it's Gillian. Who?
有点担心，因为她以为你妈妈和艾伦
Slightly concerned cos she was under the impression your mum and Alan
我们该去她家了，可他们还没来。
were due at hers and they've not turned up.
所以呢?他们是成年人。
So? They're adults.
是的，但她本来是五点钟来的。
Yes, but she was expecting them at five.
她在给他们做饭，而且…
She's cooking for them, and...
你想和她谈谈吗?
Do you want to talk to her?
吉莉安,你好!
Gillian, hi!
我打电话只是想看看他们是不是和你在一起，仅此而已。
I was just ringing to see if they were with you, that's all.
不，他们的车不在这里。他们不在这里，我刚看过。
Er, no, their car's not here. They're not here, I just looked.
我知道他们要马上离开这里。
I got the idea they were leaving here first thing.
是的，我知道。我…
They did, I know. I...
我只是想知道他们是不是因为什么原因回哈罗盖特了。
I just wondered if they'd gone back to Harrogate for whatever reason.
我不这么想。
I don't think so.
你妈妈有手机吗?
Has your mum got a mobile?
是的。你能帮我给她打个电话吗?
Yes. Would you mind ringing her for me?
我不介意他们迟到，只要他们没事就行。
I don't mind 'em being late just so long as they're all right.
确定。我一会儿打给你，给我一分钟。
Sure. I'll get back to you, give me a minute.
谢谢你！“再见。”
Thank you. 'Bye.'
再见。
Bye-bye.
她为什么打你手机?为什么?嗯…
Why is she ringing you on your mobile? Why? Well...
“你好，我是西莉亚……”嘘!“……道森。请留言。”
'Hello, this is Celia...' Shush! '..Dawson. Please leave a message.'
“谢谢你。”
'Thank you.'
嗨，妈妈，是我。
Hi, Mum, it's me.
听到留言后，请给我打个电话好吗?谢谢你！再见。
Can you give me a ring when you get this message, please? Thank you. Bye.
我需要吉莉安的电话。
I, er, need Gillian's number.
07700 900 827。
07700 900 827.
我给她打了个电话，谢谢你让我住在她家，因为你开车走了，没带我。
I rang her to say thank you for letting me stay at her house after you drove off without me.
艾伦开车送我过来的时候我跟他要了她的电话。
I got her number from Alan when he drove me over here.
而你拯救了它。
And you saved it.
嗯，是的，不，不，不……你是透明的。
Well, yes, not, not, not... You're transparent.
“你好吗?”
'Hello?'
吉莉安,嗨。我刚收到语音留言。
Gillian, hi. I'm just getting voice mail.
“好吧。”我肯定他们会来的。
'OK.' I'm sure they'll turn up.
我只是担心我爸身上带着药，你知道…
I just worry about me dad having his pills on him, you know...
．.为了他的心脏。
..for his heart.
哦，天啊，当然了。
Oh, God, yeah, of course.
如果他知道自己要迟到了，他是不会不打电话的。
'And he wouldn't not ring if he knew he was going to be late,
“当他知道我在给他们做饭的时候。”
'when he knew I was cooking for 'em.'
他只是……
He's just...
他很有礼貌，很体贴。
He's polite, he's thoughtful.
他有没有他们可能拜访过的朋友或亲戚?
Has he any friends or relatives they might have visited?
是的。是啊，我只是想先试试你。
Yeah. Yeah, I just thought I'd try you first.
我会继续打她的电话。
I'll keep trying her number.
谢谢。
Thanks.
“你能给我打电话吗?”课程。
'Will you ring me?' Course.
好吧,再见。他们可能只是被冲昏了头脑
OK, bye. They've probably just got carried away
做一些事情，忘记看时钟。
doing something and forgotten to look at the clock.
是的,不管。我做饭。
Yeah, whatever. I'm cooking.
对我来说不是。我不要你的脏东西。
Not for me. I don't want your filth.
你看，那只是…我有一个时间表。我知道我在做什么，什么时候。
You see, that's just... I have a timetable. I know what I'm cooking, when.
当你有两个高大魁梧的少年时，你就会这样安排自己，
That's the way you organise yourself when you have two strapping teenagers,
这是一份要求高、耗时长的全职工作，
a demanding, time-consuming, full-time job,
还有一个为了酒鬼甩了你的丈夫。
and a husband who dumps you for an alcoholic.
奶奶怎么了?噢,呃…
What's happening with Granny? Oh, er...
她和艾伦没按时出现在吉莉安家，
Her and Alan haven't turned up at Gillian's when they're supposed to,
和…她是,呃……
and...she's, er...
担心他们在哪里。
worried about where they are.
我去换衣服。
I'll get changed.
雨倒
RAIN POURS
马桶冲水
TOILET FLUSHES
那个马桶的冲水很厉害。
Ee, it's got a grand flush, that toilet.
维多利亚时代的人建造得很好，不是吗?
They built things properly, didn't they, the Victorians?
严格来说，这是乔治亚风格的。
Well, strictly speaking, it's Georgian.
1836年，北塔建成
1836, North Tower were completed -
在维多利亚登基前一年
year before Victoria ascended t'throne.
哦，很好。“房子的主体……”
Oh, very good. "Main body of the house..."
这里，我不知道它有这么古老，可以追溯到1514年!
Here, I didn't know it were this old - dates back to 1514!
哦,漂亮!
Oh, fancy!
是啊，幸好我们没砸窗户。
Yeah, it's a good job we didn't try smashing a window.
彩色玻璃是原始的中世纪-它是独一无二的，它是无价的。
Stained glass is original medieval - it's unique, it's priceless.
真见鬼!
Heck!
摇摇欲坠
CREAKING
她在那儿吹。我希望她不会。
There she blows. I wish she wouldn't.
我们陷入困境了，夫人!
We're in t'cludgie, missus!
他们笑了
THEY LAUGH
门打开
DOOR OPENS
脚步的方法
FOOTSTEPS APPROACH
上面有人。
There's somebody up there.
你好!
Hello!
脚步继续
FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE
哦,狗屎!不，不，不，我们没事。
Oh, shit! No, no, no, we're all right.
我们要做什么?
What are we going to do?
你好!
Hello!
我们要回楼上的卧室去……
We're going to go back up to t'bedroom...
…把门关上……还有打牌。
...and shut t'door...and play cards.
你好!
Hello!
我们被关在里面了!我们不是窃贼!我们退休人员!
We got shut in! We're not burglars! We're pensioners!
你好!
Hello!
门嘎吱嘎吱关上了
DOOR CREAKS SHUT
那是什么?
What was that?
什么都没有。
Nothing.
没什么。
It's nothing.
你还好吗?吉莉安吗?
Are you all right? Gillian?
我只是想知道他没事，仅此而已。
I just want to know that he's all right, that's all.
电话响了
PHONE RINGS
那是谁?她的
Who were that? Her.
你的母亲。还有谁?
Your mother. Who else?
疯狂的婊子!
Mad bitch!
保罗Jatri。
Paul Jatri.
我知道!保罗，该死的贾特里!
I know! Paul bloody Jatri!
我知道!为什么?
I know! Why?
上帝知道。
God knows.
不,真的……你知道为什么吗?
No, really...you know, why?
你问错人了。
You're asking t'wrong person.
除了他和尼尔·克雷斯韦尔的女儿订婚了，
Apart from t'fact that he's engaged to Neil Cresswell's lass,
他的精神年龄大得很。他是弱智。
he's got a mental age of a blancmange. He's retarded.
她找他麻烦可能不是为了他的大脑，对吧?
Well, probably not his brain she's bothering with him for, is it?
我告诉你，她一直都是这么做的。是啊，好吧!
Bloody screw loose, I tell you, she always has had. Yeah, all right!
好吧。
All right.
对不起。
Sorry.
好吧，我要开车去哈利法克斯。
Right, I'm going to drive over to Halifax.
真的吗?
Really?
是的。我把时间定在9点吧?
Yeah. Why don't I give it till nine o'clock?
是的，我把时间推迟到9点，如果我们还没有听到任何消息，我就……
Yep, I'll give it till nine and if we still haven't heard anything, I'll...
妈妈，你想让我和你一起去吗?不，不，你明天还要上学。
Do you want me to come with you, Mum? No, no, you've got school tomorrow.
电视体育评论
SPORTS COMMENTARY ON TV
电话响了
PHONE RINGS
你好!
Hello!
罗比，我是吉莉安。
Robbie, it's Gillian.
是的，我想可能是。
Yeah, I thought it might be.
我爸爸还没有出现……他本该这么做的时候
Me dad hasn't turned up... when he was supposed to,
几个小时前，我想知道拉夫有没有见过他
couple of hours ago now, and I wanted to know if Raff had seen him
也没接到他的电话什么的。
or had a phone call from him or anything.
“他在那儿吗?”你就只能做到这一点吗?
'Is he there?' Is that the best you can do?
我很抱歉?“打电话的借口。”
I'm sorry? 'Excuses for ringing up.'
她叹了口气，我不是在开玩笑，Robbie。他的心脏有问题。
SHE SIGHS I'm not mucking about, Robbie. He's got his heart problem.
我只想知道拉夫有没有他的消息。就是这么简单。
I just want to know if Raff's heard from him. It's that simple.
拉夫?嗯?
Raff? Mmm?
来吧，说说你爷爷的事。
Come on, summat about your granddad.
他叹了口气:你想要什么?
HE SIGHS What d'you want?
今晚你有爷爷的消息吗?
Have you heard from Granddad at all this evening?
“没有。”他没给你打电话，还是…
'No.' He's not rung you, or...?
为什么?
Why?
“因为我在五点钟等着他喝茶——
'Because I was expecting him at five for tea -
“他和西莉亚——”
'him and Celia -'
但是他们没有出现。
and they've not turned up.
你最后一次通话时他们在哪里?在芬兰的一家咖啡馆里，
Where were they last time you spoke? In a cafe in Elland,
“两点。”从那以后你给他打过电话吗?
'two o'clock.' Have you tried ringing him since?
当然我…!
Course I've...!
我每十分钟给他打一次电话。
I'm ringing him every ten minutes.
“所以…好吧，你打算怎么办?”
'So... Well, what are you going to do?'
她叹了口气，我得给医院打个电话，不是吗?
SHE SIGHS I'll have to ring round the hospitals, won't I?
你想让我做什么吗?
Well, do you want me to do owt?
不。
No.
要我去找他吗?
Do you want me to go looking for him?
不。
No.
你要我过去吗?
Do you want me to come over?
如果你愿意的话。
If you want.
那东西还躺在我们的沙发上吗?
Is that twat still lying on our settee?
她叹了口气:如果你想过来帮我想想下一步该怎么做，
SHE SIGHS If you want to come over and help me think about what to do next,
“非常欢迎。”
'you'd be very welcome.'
你做作业了吗?
Have you done your homework?
门吱吱的响声
DOOR CREAKS
我们应该起诉。你什么?
We should sue. You what?
明天早上，等我们从这个鬼地方出来，我们就去告他。
In the morning, when we get out of this godforsaken hole, we should sue.
这是陷阱。嗯,疏忽。
This is entrapment. Well, negligence.
我是说，如果有人…?他叹息着说
I mean, what if someone...? HE GROANS
你吃药了吗?我会很高兴的。
Have you got your pills? I'll be reet.
快点，上车。
Come on, get in.
他叹息着说
HE GROANS
碰巧那不是脚步声。
Happen they weren't footsteps.
发生……只是房子发出的声音。
Happen...just sounds a house makes.
这么老这么大的房子
A house this old, this big,
听起来像……是的。
can sound like... Yeah.
．.任何你想听起来像的东西。
..anything, anything you want it to sound like.
我不相信有鬼。我也不知道。
I don't believe in ghosts. Neither do I.
我认为一旦你兑现了你的筹码——呸!-就是这样。
I think once you've cashed your chips - pfft! - that's it.
是的…
Yeah...
尽管…
...although...
怎么啦？
What?
我一直认为天地之间有更多的东西
I've always thought there's more between heaven and earth
比我们所知的都要多。
than any of us ever know about.
哦,好吧…
Oh, well...
看不见你。
Aye.
是,……蜡烛在桌子上…之前?
Was that...candle on that table...before?
敲门
KNOCK AT DOOR
他们来了吗?
Have they turned up?
不，他们没有。你不必敲门，你知道，你可以直接进来。
No, they haven't. You don't have to knock, you know, you can just come in.
进来!
Come in!
路虎怎么了?爆炸了。
What happened to t'Land Rover? Blew up.
如何?雷电、电气故障……
How? Lightning, electrical fault...
或者有人把它烧了。焚烧吗? !
or someone torched it. Torched it?!
什么时候?就在你离开之后。
When? Just after you left.
可能是闪电。
It were probably lightning.
那么，你打算怎么处理……?我将管理。
Well, how are you going to manage...? I'll manage.
罗比认为我们应该过去帮忙找我爷爷。
Robbie thought we should come over, help look for me granddad.
他了吗?对了,嗯…
Did he? Right, well...
谢谢。
thanks.
你报警了吗?不。
Have you reported it to t'police? No.
汽车来了，是他们吗?
CAR APPROACHES Is that them?
是吗?
Is it?
看起来不像。
Doesn't look like.
是哈利和莫里斯。你爷爷的朋友。
It's Harry and Maurice. Your granddad's buddies.
你觉得有那么严重吗?你认为我应该报警吗?
Do you think it's that serious? Do you think I should report it to the police?
这取决于你。我在征求你的意见。
It's up to you. I'm asking your advice.
你想什么时候报告都行。
Well, you can report it any time you like.
我们有理由担心他的心脏状况。
There's a legitimate cause for concern cos of his heart condition.
哦,上帝。敲门
Oh, God. KNOCK AT DOOR
你想要……吗?
D'you wanna...?
你没事吧，亲爱的?
You all right, love?
我给傻蛋打了电话，但他也没收到他们的消息。
I rang Silly Bugger but he's not heard owt from 'em either.
晚上好，吉莉安。我相信有一个非常简单的解释。
Good evening, Gillian. I'm sure there's a perfectly simple explanation.
你希望如此，不是吗?
You'd hope so, wouldn't you?
骑兵的到来。
Cavalry's arrived.
告诉你吧。怎么啦？
Tell you what. What?
下雨了。
It's raining.
你没事吧，拉夫，小伙子?还不错。
You all right, Raff, lad? Not so bad.
我的上帝!他怎么了?
My God! What's happened to him?
是吗?
Eh?
你没事吧，亲爱的?呃…
You all right, love? Er...
吉莉安，有什么最新消息吗?
So, what's the latest, Gillian?
我跑遍了医院，当然这并不意味着
I've run round the hospitals, but of course that doesn't mean
他们并没有在荒野的某个地方离开路边，但是……
they haven't gone off the side of the road somewhere up in t'wilds, but...
不，他们是对的。
Nay, they'll be right.
你怎么知道他没带她去什么酒店
How do you know he hasn't taken her to some hotel somewhere
为了一个疯狂的夜晚?
for a wild night of nudge-nudge wink-wink?
他满脑子想的都是这个。
It's all he thinks about.
好吗?
Is it 'ell.
我不知道，哈利，我只是……我想他会给我打电话的。
I don't know, that, Harry, I just... I think he'd have rung me.
那我们该在什么阶段报警呢?
So, at what stage do we report it to the police?
罗比是……我随时都可以告诉她。
Well, Robbie's... I've told her any time.
考虑到他的…
Given his, er...
我想11点再做，然后…
I thought I'd leave it while 11, and then...
不。给他们打电话。
Nay. Get 'em rung.
我不想…反应过度。
Well, I don't want to...overreact.
你不想往最坏的方面想。这就是问题所在。
You don't want to think the worst. That's the thing.
但是…考虑到他……
But...given his...
他们会很感激的，警察，可能还有别的事要做。
They'll be grateful, t'police - probably got bugger all else to do.
别那样看着我。我实话实说。
Don't look at me like that. I tell it like it is.
我也想，但他偶尔会和你们一起出去吃晚饭
Well, I would, but he has, on occasion, been out supping with you lot all hours
在此之前，便出现了胡言乱语
before now, then turned up talking gibberish
裤腿卷起来，外套穿反了。
with his trouser legs rolled up and his coat on inside out.
是啊，那太不幸了。
Yes, well, that was...unfortunate.
今天是他的生日!你怎么了?
It were his birthday! What's up with you?
错过什么?不，只是该出现的时候没出现。
Missing? No, just not turned up when they were supposed to.
那你觉得他们在哪里?
So, well, where do you think they are?
我不知道!没人知道，那是…
I've got no idea! Nobody does, that's...
对不起，凯特。我只是…
I'm sorry, Kate. I'm just...
伤了?你当然是。没关系。
Wound up? Course you are. That's all right.
我敢肯定她绝对……
I'm sure she's absolutely...
课程。当然可以。
Course. Of course.
不过，天黑后她通常不出去，这就是问题所在。
She doesn't go out after dark, as a rule, though, that's the thing.
她的眼睛和以前不一样了，而且……
Her eyes aren't what they were, and...
会有解释的。
There'll be an explanation.
听着，有什么我能帮忙的就打电话给我。
Listen, ring me if there's anything I can do.
或者你只是想找个人聊聊。
Or if you just want to talk to someone.
你打电话找我干什么?
What were you ringing me for?
哦!
Oh!
现在看来不那么重要了。
It doesn't seem so important now.
只是…你说我们应该离开。
Just...you said we should go away.
“这个周末。
'For the weekend.
“可能在某个地方一起。
'Together, somewhere, possibly.
“我想知道你是不是认真的，如果你是认真的，”
'And I wanted to know if you meant it, and if you did,'
如果我应该修理什么东西
if I should fix something up.
我们能晚点再谈吗?
Can we talk about it later?
是的，当然。
Yeah, of course.
嗨。有什么消息吗?我妈妈和罗比在那边跟警察说话。
Hi. Is there any news? Me mum's through there with Robbie talking to a uniform.
你是西莉亚的女儿吗?
Are you Celia's lass?
是的,那是……
Yes, that's...
哈利华莱士。
Harry Wallace.
我是莫里斯·普莱斯。
This is Maurice Price.
他们是我爷爷的朋友。啊。
They're me granddad's pals. Ah.
希望你妈妈没有把他引入歧途。是…?
I hope your mother's not been leading him astray. Been...?
闭嘴。拉斯很担心。
Shut up. Lass is worried.
她知道我在开玩笑。
She knows I'm joking.
我知道你是个医生!
I understand you're a doctor!
我…是的。
I'm... Yeah.
她是吗?
Is she?
你能看看我的脚吗?
Will you look at my foot?
把你的脚拿开。我血液循环不好。
Put your foot away. I've got poor circulation.
我不是医生
I'm not a medical doctor.
然后呢?化学。
What then, then? Chemistry.
化学，他们能做到吗?
Chemistry, can they do that?
忽略他。
Ignore him.
他的农村。
He's rural.
我也有疝气。我想是疝气。你想看一看吗?
I've a hernia as well. I think it's a hernia. Do you want to have a look?
这不是我的…
It's not really my...
我们知道发生了什么吗?没有任何进展。
Do we know what's happening? There's been no developments.
你为什么不坐下呢，亲爱的?
Why don't you sit down, love?
化学。
Chemistry.
玛格丽特·撒切尔在牛津大学读化学。
Margaret Thatcher read chemistry at Oxford.
是的，我在另一所大学。
Yes, well, I was in a different college.
是啊，我会道歉的。
Yeah, and I'd be apologising an' all.
发生了什么事?什么都没有。什么都没有。
What's happened? Nothing. Nothing.
就像我在电话里说的，我们觉得没什么好损失的，
It were just, like I said on t'phone, we decided there was nothing to lose,
尽快报告他们失踪，所以....
reporting 'em missing sooner rather than later, so....
你还好吗?是的。是的。是吗?
Are you all right? Yeah. Yeah. Are you?
是的。
Yeah.
他们已经做了描述，他们可以…
They've taken a description, and they can...
他们要做什么，Robbie?检查银行卡最后一次使用的时间，
What are they going to do, Robbie? Check when the bank cards were last used,
他们最后一次使用手机的时间。然后我们就跑
when their mobiles were last used. And then we'll run
对他们的车辆进行ANPR检查那是什么?
an ANPR check on their vehicle. What's that?
荷兰的两倍。这就像车牌识别。
Double Dutch. It's like vehicle plate recognition.
我们可以看到他们最后被摄像头拍到的地方。看看他们要去哪里。
We can see where they were last picked up on cameras. See where they were heading.
那我们什么时候能知道呢?只要我们得到楼上的授权去追查。
So when will we know anything? As soon as we get authority from upstairs to pursue it.
跟我们谈话的那个小伙子要直接去见警长，所以…
The lad that we spoke to is going straight up to see t'Super, so...
最好的办法是……
Best thing we can...
他们说我们最好还是回家。
They said best thing we can do is go home.
他们知道了会给我们打电话的。
They'll ring us when they know owt.
你们为什么不回家呢，伙计们?
Why don't you go home, lads?
如果我需要你，我会给你打电话。如果有什么消息。
I'll ring you if I need you. If there's any news.
“你好，我是西莉亚·道森。请留下……”
'Hello, this is Celia Dawson. Please leave...'
你是谁?
Who IS that?
保罗……Jatri。
Paul...Jatri.
他是个白痴。
He's an idiot.
保罗Jat……?那就是你…?
Paul Jat...? Is that the bloke you...?
是的。但我没有那样对他。
Yeah. But I didn't do that to him.
我只是碰伤了他。
I just bruised him.
那是另一个人。
That was somebody else.
正确的。
Right.
他不受欢迎。
He's not popular.
是什么……他在这里做什么?
So what's... What's he doing here?
这是个好问题。
That's a good question.
不要问。
Don't ask.
(你拿着那个量尺干什么?)
(What were you doing with that dipstick?)
别责怪我，我已经受够了。
Don't start on me, I've enough on.
我只是…
I just...
我所做的是……
What I do is...
你以为我会成为修女吗?
You think I'm going to be a nun?
不!不。艾迪已经死了十年了。
No! No. Eddie's been dead for ten years.
你真以为从那以后我就没跟别人睡过吗?
D'you seriously think I haven't slept with other people since then?
我只是…这关你什么事?
I just... What's it to you?
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
关于我们之间的不愉快。
About all the unpleasantness there's been between us.
不愉快?
Unpleasantness?
想让别人相信我有问题吗?
Trying to convince people that I've got a screw loose?
我谋杀了自己的丈夫?想让拉菲相信吗?我在发泄。
That I murdered my own husband? Trying to make Raffy believe that? I was lashing out.
十年?我很抱歉。
For ten years? I'm sorry.
我只是觉得……
I just think...
…你让自己失望了。
...you let yourself down.
为一连串的…随便吧，像他一样。
Bothering with a streak of...whatever, like him.
你应该做得更好。
You're better than that.
我以为……
I thought...
…在艾迪死后，你是最重要的
...after Eddie died, you of all people
会帮助我，支持我。
would help me, support me.
妈的，我错了，对吧?
Shit, I was wrong, wasn't it?
你以为我会忘记你对我做的事吗?
D'you think I'm going to forget what you tried to do to me?
你让我经历了什么?
What you put me through?
我们可以组成一个完美的团队。
We could make an all-right team.
你，我，还有拉夫，不是吗?
You, me, an' Raff, couldn't we?
你烧了我的路虎吗?
Did you torch my Land Rover?
不!
No!
如果克雷斯韦尔家族这么做了，我会……
If the Cresswells did, I will...
我会抓住他们的。
I'll get 'em.
这是……
That's...
嗯…
Um...
我很感激你的道歉，Robbie。
I'm appreciating the apology, Robbie.
它很好。
It's fine.
上床睡觉。
Go to bed.
一有消息我就通知你。
I'll let you know the second we hear owt.
我们都无能为力。
There's nowt any of us can do.
至少闭上眼睛吧，你明天还要上学。
Go shut your eyes at least, you've got school tomorrow.
电话响了
PHONE RINGS
喂?
Hello?
是的，它是。
Yes, it is.
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
4.32,对吧。
4.32, right.
对布拉德福德? !
Towards Bradford?!
无道?
Godley Lane?
他不认识那边的人。
He doesn't know anybody over that way.
等一下。
Hang on a minute.
他们被摄像头拍到，或者他们的注册号是。
They were caught on camera, or their registration number was.
沿着哈利法克斯另一边的戈德利巷，驶向布拉德福德。
Driving up Godley Lane, the other side of Halifax, towards Bradford.
没有进一步的目击。正确的。所以你……?
No further sightings. Right. So you're...?
他们最初集中在那片区域。
They're concentrating on that area round there initially.
那附近有什么?
What is there around there?
什么都没有，只有南屋厅，仅此而已。
There's nothing, there's Southowram Hall, that's about it.
喃喃自语:你可以在southwram大厅结婚。他说了什么?
MUMBLING: You can get married at Southowram Hall. What's he said?
他说你可以在索瑟伦庄园结婚。
He said you can get married at Southowram Hall.
他们在找婚礼场地。
They were looking for a wedding venue.
电视剧
TV PLAYS
你和妈妈现在还在离婚吗?
Are you and Mum still getting divorced then now, or what?
哦,好吧…
Oh, well...
恐怕我不知道。
I'm afraid I don't know.
你不能说服她吗?
Can't you win her round?
你不能…给她买些花什么的?
Can't you...buy her some flowers or something?
嗯，我有。几乎。
Well, I had. Almost.
赢得了她的支持。我认为。然后……
Won her round. I think. And then...
别怪我。我不是!
Don't you blame me. I wasn't!
我不是。
I wasn't.
不过你确实误会了。
Although you did get the wrong end of the stick.
是啊，如果你还没发现…一开始就是个贱人
Yeah, well, if you hadn't started seeing that...bitch in the first place,
不会有任何错误的一端给任何人抓住，不是吗?
there wouldn't be any wrong end of any sticks for anybody to get hold of, would there?
是的,很好。我们现在真的要争论这个吗?重点是，你再也见不到朱蒂丝了，
Yeah, fine. Are we really going to argue about this now? The point is, you're not seeing Judith any more,
所以你不需要再离婚了。
so you don't need to get divorced any more.
不，重点是，她不能再信任他了，不能再信任他了。
No, the point is, she can't trust him any more, any further than she can throw him.
所以这并不像说“你不能给她买些花吗?”那么天真和愚蠢。
So it's not just as naive and dumb as saying, "Can't you buy her some flowers?!"
尿了!是啊，成熟点吧!
Piss off! Yeah, well, grow up!
你成熟点吧!冷静点。停止它!阻止它。
You grow up! Just calm down. Stop it! Stop it.
我们都很担心奶奶，这不是一个好办法…
We're all worried about Gran, and this isn't a good way to...
他嗤之以鼻
HE SNIFFS
我相信我和妈妈能解决问题。
I'm sure me and Mum can sort things out.
这些事有时需要时间，仅此而已。
These things take time, sometimes, that's all.
还有一点善意。
And a bit of goodwill.
我很抱歉那天把我丈夫强加给你。
I'm sorry I inflicted my husband on you the other day.
哦，好吧，不用道歉。
Oh, well, don't apologise.
我很抱歉我儿子在你们面前被捕了…
I'm sorry my son got arrested in front of you all...
由他自己…
by his own...
叔叔。
uncle.
所以他……拉夫揍了躺在你沙发上的那个家伙。
So he... Raff beat up the bloke that's lying on your couch.
是的。是的,他……
Yeah. Yeah, he...
他是保罗。他的……
He's Paul. He's...
我和保罗是朋友
We're friends, me and Paul,
拉夫觉得我们不仅仅是朋友
and Raff got it into his head that we were more than friends
他不喜欢这样。所以他……
and he didn't like that. So he...
然后又有人把他打得更狠?是的。
Then someone else beat him up even more? Yeah.
他女朋友的兄弟们听到了风声，
His girlfriend's brothers got wind of what'd been said,
而且，他们是一群令人讨厌的人。
and, well, they're a pretty unpleasant lot.
哦……他断腿是因为什么误会吗?
Oh... He's got broken limbs because of some misunderstanding?
那么，一切都解决了吗?
So, has everything settled down?
然后呢?现在?呃，在你那边?
Then? Now? Er, at your end?
或者…?
Or...?
哦!呃…
Oh! Er...
我和约翰。
Me and John.
是的。
Yeah.
远不止于此。
It's beyond that.
他跟你说了什么?
What did he tell you?
哦，那个，呃……
Oh, that, er...
她清喉咙
SHE CLEARS THROAT
…他有过一段风流韵事
...he'd had a fling,
和…
and...
是啊，他希望自己没这么做。
Yeah, that he wished he hadn't.
真的吗?嗯。他只是想…
Really? Mmm. And that he wanted just to...
…回去吧。
...get back with you.
如果他明天遇到想和他一起做的人他还会再做的。
Well, he'd do it again tomorrow if he met someone else he wanted to do it with.
他就是这么抱歉。
That's how sorry he is.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
累了。
Tired.
他们到底在哪?!
Where the hell are they?!
对不起。
Sorry.
我很抱歉。这对谁都没有帮助。
I'm sorry. That helps no-one.
不，你没事的。你担心。喝点白兰地。是的,真的。
No, you're all right. You're worried. Have a drop of brandy. Yes, actually.
这不是，呃，误会。
It wasn't, er, a misunderstanding.
我…
I...
我不知道。我都不知道我为什么要告诉你。
I don't know. I don't even know why I'm telling you.
不过拉夫一般不会这么做。
Except that Raff doesn't generally behave like that.
他的……他不是暴徒。他是个好孩子。
He's... He's not a thug. He's a grand lad.
比我应得的好。
Better than I deserve.
他就像我爸爸。
He's like my dad.
他有一个伟大的连胜纪录
He's got a big streak
他身上刻下了一些体面的印记。
of something very decent etched right through him.
我没有。
And I haven't.
我一团糟。
I'm a mess.
你知道的。
Well, you know that.
你第一次见到我的时候就明白了。
Put your finger on it the first time you met me.
我不该那么说的。这很愚蠢。我不是故意的，我是…
I shouldn't have said that. It was stupid. I didn't mean it, it was...
我一直在…
I've been...
我一直很沮丧。
I've been depressed.
好几个月了。
For months.
把东西装瓶，然后……
Bottling things up and then...
它出来了，你说了些愚蠢、下流、愚蠢的话，
it comes out, and you say things - silly, nasty, stupid things,
你根本不是那个意思，而且自从…
things you don't even mean, and it's since...
这是自…
It's since...
大多数时候，我觉得我只是在压抑自己的工作，
I feel like I'm only just holding my job down, most days,
这就是……
and that's...
这是可怕的。
It's terrifying.
抱歉，你也不需要知道这个。
Sorry, you don't need to know that, either.
电话响了
PHONE RINGS
喂?
Hello?
他们找到车了。
They've found the car.
在康布里伍德南瑟伦大厅楼上的停车场里。
In the car park above Southowram Hall in Cumbry Wood.
但不是他们?
But not them?
喂?
Hello?
我们现在解雇了很多警官。
We're turning a good number of officers out now.
这附近有什么地方吗
Is there anywhere at all in the vicinity
你觉得他们最有可能去哪了?
where you think they're most likely to have gone?
我能帮你吗?我是馆长。你的中士打电话给我。
Can I help you? I'm the curator. Your sergeant rang me.
我尽快赶过来了。两个退休?
I got here as soon as I could. Two pensioners?
您是钥匙持有者吗，先生?其中一个。
Are you the key holder, sir? One of them.
我可以为你开门，非常欢迎，但我们昨天没开门。
I can open up for you, you're more than welcome, but we weren't open yesterday.
我们星期一不营业。从星期天起我们就没有客人了。
We don't open on a Monday. We've had no visitors since Sunday.
我能问一下，他们俩最近有抑郁吗?
Can I ask, has either of them been depressed at all lately?
不!一点也不!
No! Not at all!
完全相反!他们彼此相爱。
Completely the opposite! They're in love with each other.
他们从来没有这么快乐过!
They've never been happier!
对，就是这样。奇怪的事情发生了。
Right, that's it. Summat weird's happening.
为什么车在那里，他们不在里面?
Why's the car there and them not in it?
然后问我他们最近有没有抑郁过?
And asking me if either of them has been depressed lately?
他们只是想排除一切可能，吉莉安。这是例行公事。
They're just trying to rule things out, Gillian. It's routine.
他们只是在想最好的办法。
They're just trying to think of the best way forward.
这没有什么邪恶的。他不像你那么了解他们。
There's nothing sinister about it. He doesn't know 'em like you do.
他只是想建立一幅画面。他只是在做他的工作。
He's just trying to build up a picture. He's just doing his job.
你想开车过去吗?我不会。
Do you want to drive over there? I wouldn't.
说实话，你最好待在这里，暖和点。
Honestly, you're best off here, in t'warm.
如果你们去那里，只会更加紧张。
You're only going to wind yourselves up even more if you go over there.
让他们继续吧。他们知道自己在做什么。
Let them get on with it. They know what they're doing.
听着，这种事时有发生……每一个星期。
Look, stuff like this happens... every week.
这并不罕见。
It's not unusual.
十有八九，会有完美的…
Nine times out of ten, there's a perfectly...
不一定是一个合理的解释，但总有一个解释。
Well, not necessarily a rational explanation, but there's an explanation.
人们马上就来了。他们经常因为这样的小题大做而感到尴尬!
People turn up right as rain. They're often embarrassed there's been such a fuss!
我只希望他在某个温暖的地方。
I just hope he's warm somewhere.
别在这外面。我为什么不过去呢?
Not out in this. Why don't I go over there?
我可能会发现一些问题。而且我能更好地让你了解最新情况。
I might find summat out. And I can keep you up to date better.
你想去吗?
Do you want to?
是的。
Yeah.
每天早上醒来都能看到这个感觉真好。
It's very nice, waking up to this every morning.
嗯,是的。
Well, yeah.
在夏天。
In summer.
我爸爸…
Me dad...
…我在说，如果西莉亚来和我们一起住，你会怎么想?
...was saying, how would you feel if Celia came to live with us here?
他只是在猜测。我觉得他们还没做决定。
He was just speculating. I don't think they've made a decision.
我说我很乐意，但我不知道她冬天会怎么过。
And I said I'd be delighted, but I don't know how she'd go on in winter.
风会把你吹倒。
Wind can knock you over.
去年我们有八英尺高的积雪。
We had eight-foot snowdrifts last year.
不，我想象不出她挤牛奶的样子。
No, I can't quite picture her milking cows.
我没有奶牛。
I don't have any cows.
只羊。
Just sheep.
我一直想要一个农场。
I always wanted a farm.
我不知道为什么。我不是天生的。
I don't know why. I wasn't born into it.
是你丈夫吗?上帝,不!
Was your husband? God, no!
骑自行车和喝酒是他的两大职业选择。
Biking and boozing were his two big career choices.
是我做了所有的讨价还价和调查。
It was me that did all the wheeling and dealing and finding out.
他很喜欢。嗯，他很喜欢。但是…
He liked it. Well, he loved it. But...
他在哪里?
Where is he?
死了。
Dead.
十年，下次再来。
Ten years, this next time.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
用劈柴机打碎了他的头骨。
Smashed his skull with a log splitter.
哦!在t 'barn。
Oh! In t'barn.
耶稣。
Jesus.
失血过多而死。
Bled to death.
这样也好。
Which was just as well.
如果他能活下来，他的大脑也会受损。
He'd have had brain damage if he'd survived.
我找到他了。那是愉快的!
I found him. That was pleasant!
是意外吗?
Was it an accident?
不。
No.
哦,嗯。
Oh, eh.
对不起。
Sorry.
你觉得他们死了吗?不。
Do you think they're dead? No.
不，我觉得我们不该这么想。
No, I don't think we should assume that.
他爱她，你知道的。这么多。
He loves her, you know. So much.
他的……它是美丽的。
He's... It's beautiful.
这是非凡的。
It's extraordinary.
不管发生了什么，他都会照顾她的。
Whatever has happened, he'll be looking after her.
我知道。
I know that.
I know.
但这让我很困扰。
It's bothered me, though.
关于我母亲的事…
That thing about me mother...
没有把这个信息传递给他。
not passing on that message to him.
你妈妈的。
From your mum.
因为，你知道，我想……
Because, you know, I suppose...
．.你想要能够想象她会为他感到高兴。
..you want to be able to think that she'd have been happy for him.
过了这么久才见到西莉亚。
Meeting up with Celia after all this time.
他一直很……
He's been so...
. .快乐。
..happy.
但也许她不会。
But maybe she wouldn't have been.
她嫉妒到一开始就阻止他们在一起。
She were jealous enough to stop 'em getting together in t'first place.
也许她真的…!
Maybe she'd have been really...!
她这么做的时候还是个青少年。
She was a teenager when she did that.
她当时和拉夫现在一样大——没有人会因此而责怪她。
She was the same age Raff is now - nobody can hold that against her.
但是她欺骗了他……
But she deceived him...
…他们的一生。
...all their lives.
而他只是刚刚发现。
And he's only just found out.
我想这让他很难过。
And I think it's upset him.
他什么也没说。不。
He hasn't said owt. No.
如果你爸爸没有娶你妈妈，我妈妈没有嫁给我爸爸，
If your dad hadn't married your mum, and my mum hadn't married my dad,
我们俩都不会在这里，所以…或者我们可以成为姐妹。
neither of us would be here, so... Or we could've been sisters.
是啊，那就…灾难。
Yeah, well that would have been a... Disaster.
他们笑了
THEY LAUGH
我想我们应该感谢你妈妈默默为她所做的一切。
I think we should be very grateful to your mum on the quiet for doing what she did.
是的。
Yeah.
你的父母很高兴，是吗?是的,是的!
Your parents were happy, weren't they? Yeah, yeah!
那好吧!
Well, then!
他们似乎一直都是。
They always seemed to be.
不是你的吗?
Weren't yours?
嗯…
Well...
这就是奇怪的地方。
that's what's so odd.
她突然和我过去45年认识的那个人完全不一样了。
She's suddenly such a different person to the one I've known for the last 45 years.
我突然觉得她好像还活着，好像我从没见过她。
It's suddenly like she's alive, like I've never seen her before.
锁和门咔哒响
LOCKS AND DOORS CLICK
遥远的声音
DISTANT VOICES
西莉亚?西莉亚!
Celia? Celia!
哦，我一直在睡觉。
Oh, I've been asleep.
Ssh !Ssh !
Ssh! Ssh!
现在几点了?
What time is it?
噢，差二十分八点了!
Oh, it's twenty to eight!
哦，永远不会!
Oh, it's never!
它是!
It is!
哦!哦，我僵了!
Oh! Ooh, I'm stiff!
是的。
Yeah.
来吧。
Come on.
你还好吗?是的。
Are you all right? Yeah.
我想是的。
I think so.
是吗?
Are you?
哦，我不知道!
Oh, I've no idea!
我肯定在我们回到床上之前就把门关上了。
I'm sure I shut that door before we got back into bed.
哦，我们走吧。
Oh, let's get out of here.
我并不乐观。他们都70多岁了，
I'm not optimistic. Both in their 70s,
整晚都在外面。你好!
out all night. Hello!
我们被关在里面了!你负责吗?
We've been shut in! Are you in charge?
我,呃……我们带了些巧克力，我们必须带。
I, er... We took some chocolate, we had to.
我在收银台留下了一张5英镑的钞票。
I've left a £5 note by the till.
你还好吗?我整理了床铺。
Are you all right? And I made the bed.
你应该打电话求救的。我们做不到!
You should have rung for help. We couldn't make it work!
而且你的手机也收不到信号!你必须按9号铃打外线。
And you can't get a signal on t'mobile! You've to ring 9 for an outside line.
你应该把它写在手机旁边的小卡片上，
Well, you should have it written by the phone on a bit of card,
这样人们就会知道了。我们昨天不营业。
then folk would know. We weren't open yesterday.
那扇门。我们有个送货…
That door was. We had a delivery...
大约四点半?我的天啊!
About half past fourish? Oh, my God!
我们等着买票。
We waited to buy tickets.
但是没有人来，所以我们在那里闲逛，寻找一个人。
Only nobody came, so we wandered through there, looking for somebody.
是啊，然后我们听到关门的声音。就是这样。
Yeah, and then we heard the door slam. And that was that.
我很惊讶我们没有启动警报。
I'm amazed we didn't set t'alarm off.
哦，该死的。
Oh, bloody hell.
你现在没法给我们接通外线，对吧?
You couldn't get us an outside line right now, could you?
只会有人想知道我们到底在哪里!
Only there'll be people wondering where the heck we are!
是的。有。
Yeah. There are.
西约克郡一半的警察都在找你!
Half of West Yorkshire Police are out looking for you!
约翰:“你打算怎么处理工作?”
JOHN: 'What are you going to do about work?'
我已经和副局长谈过了。他们可以在没有我的情况下维持下去，只要…
I've spoken to the deputy heads. They can keep things afloat without me for as long as, um...
我以为我们现在已经有所了解了。
I thought we'd know something by now.
孩子们怎么样了?我不会送劳伦斯去上学的。
How are the boys? I'm not sending Lawrence to school.
反正威廉今天也没有考试，但他们俩都没合眼。
William's not got any exams today anyway, but neither of them slept a wink.
“嗯，我们谁也没见过。”它很好。
'Well, none of us have.' It's fine.
电话响得很好。
PHONE RINGS Fine.
你好!爷爷!
Hello! Granddad!
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
你们俩都没事吧?
Are you both all right?
夫人……博士吗?卡洛琳在这里。她整晚都在这里…
Mrs... Dr? Caroline's here. She's been here all night with...
我能跟她谈谈吗?她想和西莉亚谈谈。
Can I talk to her? She wants to talk to Celia.
妈妈?
Mum?
吉莉安!妈妈!
Gillian! Mum!
吉莉安!吉莉安!
Gillian! Gillian!
他们很好。他们很好!他们绝对没问题。
They're fine. They're fine! They're absolutely fine.
他们被关在南大厅里了。
They got shut inside Southowram Hall.
他们一直在打牌和吃巧克力!
They've been playing cards and eating chocolate!
关在? !是啊!
Shut in?! Yeah!
警察没想过要先进去看看吗?!
Didn't t'police think to look in there first?!
他们笑了
THEY LAUGH
哦，我要杀了他!
Oh, I'll kill him!
慵懒的…!
Dozy...!
只有他能自己去……!
Only he could go getting himself in a...!
吉莉安笑
GILLIAN LAUGHS
哦!
Oh!
好了，学校。
OK, so, school.
妈妈说你不必去，所以我建议你卧床休息，可能的话，玩Xbox。
Mum says you don't have to go, so I suggest bed, day off, Xbox, possibly.
是的!大胆去做吧。显然不是你。
Yes! Go for it. Not you, obviously.
你必须复习。
You have to revise.
很遗憾，我得去超市。
I, sadly, have to go to the supermarket.
他呻吟道:“你最好还是上楼，别挡道。”
HE GROANS You'll be better off upstairs, out of t'way.
你要睡在哪里?在t 'settee。
Where will you sleep? On t'settee.
我会把你的车藏在谷仓里，如果有人来找你…
I'll hide your car in t'barn, then if anybody comes looking for you...
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
他们唉声叹气
THEY GROAN AND GASP
．.我会告诉他们你不在这里。
..I'll tell 'em you're not here.
她呼气了，好吗?
SHE EXHALES OK?
他们喘着气呻吟着
THEY GASP AND GROAN
好的。
OK.
对吧……
Right...
你……在我有机会向我爸爸解释之前不要声张
you...keep it quiet till I've had a chance to explain to me dad
你他妈在这儿干什么。
what the bloody hell you're doing here.
然后……噢!
Then... Ow!
．.当我这样做的时候，我不想听到任何粗俗的评论
..when I have, I don't want any vulgar comments
出现在西莉亚面前!
of any description in front of Celia!
完全理解了吗?
Is that absolutely understood?
因为如果你这么做，你就得滚蛋了，比你说"复合骨折"还快。
Cos you'll be out on your arse if you do, faster than you can say "compound fracture".
我说过你有什么问题吗?
Now, is there anything I've said you're having trouble with?
他呻吟着说:你给我止痛药了吗?
HE GROANS Have you got me painkillers?
我去给你倒点水。
I'll get you some water.
真希望我能早点把他关进来。
I wish I'd have thought to stick him in here sooner.
拉夫:妈妈，他们来了!比;
RAFF: Mum, they're here! &gt;
发生了什么事? !哦!
What happened?! Oh!
你不是应该在工作吗?是的。
Shouldn't you be at work? Yes.
嘿，那是谁的车?昨晚一屋子人都坐满了想知道你到底去哪了。
Hey, whose car is that? We had a full house last night trying to work out where the hell you were.
嘿!那是我们的路虎吗?
Hey! Is that our Land Rover?!
它被闪电击中了。
It was hit by lightning.
你还好吗?僵硬、冰冷、头脑迟钝。
Are you all right? Stiff, cold and muzzy-headed.
我希望警察给那个把你锁在里面的人一枚火箭
I hope the police gave whoever locked you in a rocket up their...
哦，那是肯定的。
ROBBIE: Oh, that's guaranteed.
我们以为你私奔了!嗯，好主意。
We thought you'd eloped! Eh, that's a good idea.
你饿了吗?
Are you hungry?
哦，一杯加糖的好茶，我想。
Oh, a nice cup of tea with a bit of sugar, I think.
哦，我们可以喝茶!他需要他的药!
Oh, we can do tea! And he needs his pills!
你说那是谁的车?
Hey, whose car did you say that were?
哦，是…是保罗·贾特里的。
Oh, it's, um... It's Paul Jatri's.
保罗Jatri ?是啊!
Paul Jatri? Yeah!
是的,他是……我去烧壶水。
Yeah, he's... I'll get t'kettle on.
你感觉怎么样?
How do you feel?
用劳伦斯的话来说，就像呕吐热身一样。
Oh, like puke warmed up, to quote our Lawrence.
嗨。啊。
Hi. Ah.
很抱歉。
Sorry about this.
两个月的房租。
Two months' rent.
你真是太好了。
You really are very kind.
约翰?你还好吗?
John? Are you all right?
我昨晚没怎么睡。
Oh, didn't get much sleep last night.
天啊，我不是故意让你惊慌的!我没有勒索你!
God, I didn't mean for you to get panicky! I'm not blackmailing you!
我岳母失踪了。哦。
My mother-in-law went missing. Oh.
她是……?很好。她很好。
Is she...? Fine. She's fine.
她绝对没事。
She's absolutely fine.
哦，那太好了。
Oh, well, that's...good.
我想问问蒂姆·霍斯金斯能不能让我回去工作
I was thinking of asking Tim Hoskins if I could have my old job back
在大学图书馆。
at the university library.
朱蒂丝，是蒂姆·霍斯金斯让你离开的。
Judith, it was Tim Hoskins who asked you to leave.
我知道，但我想，如果你能帮我说句话，
Yes, I know, but I thought, if you could put a word in for me,
如果你告诉他我在好转
if you told him that I'm getting better
我正在处理这件事
and I'm dealing with it and...
我想他现在已经取代你了。
I imagine he's replaced you by now.
是的，但下次有空缺的时候。
Yes, but next time there's a vacancy.
朱迪思,不!
Judith, no!
我去告诉卡洛琳我给了你那笔钱，好吗?
I'm going to tell Caroline I've given you that money, all right?
求你了，别再向我要了。我认为在就业方面，
And please, don't ask me for any more. I think as regards employment,
你得把眼光放在更现实的事情上。说“现实”，就说“卑微”?
you're going to have to set your sights on something more realistic. For "realistic", read "menial"?!
你要把我介绍给你的出版商!你有什么成品要给他看吗?
You WERE going to introduce me to your publisher! Have you got anything finished to show him?
我又写了一章，那是第四章!
I've written another chapter, that's four!
朱蒂丝，我已经解释过了。没人会出版几章。我知道!
Judith, I've explained this. No-one's going to publish a few chapters. I know that!
没有人会因为他们的力量给你预支钱。
And no-one's going to advance you some money on the strength of them.
我们又回到了现实世界!
Again, we come back to living in the real world!
哦，你真是个傲慢的……
Oh, you're a patronising...!
不，朱蒂丝，我是实话实说。
No, Judith, I'm telling it to you like it is.
也许是时候有人这么做了。
It's possibly time someone did.
你曾经说过我有成为小说家的潜力。是的，我做到了!
You used to say I had a potential as a novelist. Yes, I did!
你仍然需要投入时间!
You still have to put the hours in!
你还得保持清醒足够长的时间才能真正把它写下来!
You still have to stay sober long enough to actually get it down in black and white!
你不能靠潜力来谋生!
You can't make a career and a living out of potential!
你得让它更上一层楼。
You've got to take it to the next level.
如果你明白我在说什么，并继续做下去，你最后可能会感谢我。
If you ever understand what I'm saying, and simply got on with it, you'd probably thank me in the end.
事实上……尿了!
As it is... Piss off!
完全正确。
Exactly.
如果……如果我曾经认为你真的在努力，我希望
If... If I ever did think you were genuinely making an effort, I hope -
我希望我能帮助你。
I HOPE - I would help you.
现在就是这样了。
As it is, that's it now.
我们应该起诉!
We should sue!
我是说，你们都担心死了。
I mean, you lot have been worried out of your minds.
我和艾伦都受到了创伤。疏忽!
Me and Alan's traumatised. It's negligence!
但是他们免费给你提供了婚礼场地?
But they've offered you the venue free of charge for the wedding?
嗯嗯。你不能接受这一点然后起诉他们，对吧?
Mm-hm. Well, you can't accept that and sue them, can you?
嗯,没有。
Well, no.
而且非常优雅。
And it is very classy.
不可能有那么多人能在那里结婚。
There can't be so many can afford to get married there.
这对教会来说是一件好事!
And it would be one in the eye for the church!
我们被拒绝了!我告诉过你吗?
We got turned down! Did I tell you?
我是说，你能相信吗?
I mean, can you believe it?!
我和艾伦小时候在教堂里受苦的时光。
The hours me and Alan have sat suffering in that church when we were kids.
现在我们连结婚的资格都没有了!
And now we don't even qualify to get wed in it!
这是犯罪!
It's criminal!
你和保罗·贾特里有一腿吗!
You've been having a fling with Paul Jatri?!
你能相信吗?哦，他才15岁!
Can you believe it? Oh, he's only 15!
不，爸爸，那是违法的。他是22。
No, Dad, that would be illegal. He's 22.
是啊，你45岁了!你最近照镜子了吗?
Yeah, and you're 45! Have you looked in t'mirror lately?
这不是一时的冲动!只是……他笑着说
It wasn't a fling! It was just... HE LAUGHS
这一点都不好笑。真是一团糟!这就是为什么聪明的乞丐被逮捕了!
It's not funny. It's a mess! That's why clever beggar got arrested!
然后保罗的女朋友听到了风声
And then Paul's girlfriend got wind of it and...
他有女朋友了?!
He's got a girlfriend?!
他和尼尔·克雷斯韦尔的女儿订婚了!
He's engaged to Neil Creswell's lass!
她的哥哥们对他的虐待更甚!糟糕得多!
Her brothers have done him over even worse! A hell of a lot worse!
然后是我的土地……
Then there's my Land...
所以他才在楼上我的床上
That's why he's upstairs in my bed
腿断了，下巴断了，三根肋骨断了
with a broken leg, a bust jaw, three cracked ribs
一只手的手指都碎成了…鸡奸!
and the fingers on one hand all smashed to...buggery!
你能相信吗?他无处可去了!
Can you believe it? He's got nowhere else to go!
总是你挑的!
You always did pick 'em!
我已经跟他说清楚了，他没有…
I've made it clear to him, he hasn't...
在西莉亚面前做或说任何粗鲁或挑衅的话
to do or say anything crude or provocative in front of Celia,
我觉得他不会的
which I don't think he will.
他目前没有能力。哦，这是你的房子。
He's not capable at the minute. Oh, it's your house.
别这么说，爷爷!叫她把他甩了!
Don't say that, Granddad! Tell her to chuck him out!
你不是真的要和罗比分手吧?
You're not really stopping with Robbie?
嗯…我为什么要来这里?
Well...well, why would I want to be here?
我不介意她有男朋友，但为什么她就不能选一个a -不是白痴的呢，
I don't mind her having a boyfriend, but why can't she pick somebody who A - isn't a dickhead,
B -没有比她年轻300岁，C -没有和别人订婚!
B - isn't 300 years younger than she is, and C - wasn't engaged to somebody else!
所以我并不完美!我很惊讶这对你来说是个新闻!
So I'm not perfect! I'm amazed this is news to you!
我说过我是吗?!他叹了口气
Have I ever claimed to be?! HE SIGHS
哦!
Oh!
那家伙订婚了!
Fella that's engaged!
是的!好吧!把我钉在十字架上吧!
Yes! All right! So crucify me!
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
过几天我可能会去做手术。
I might pop down to t'surgery in the next few days.
约个时间，做个小检查。
Make a little appointment, just have a little check-up.
你是……?不，这不是……
Are you...? No, it's nowt...
这是一种刺痛。
It's a twinge.
昨晚有一两次。我现在就打电话。
Once or twice last night. I'll ring up now.
不，不，我来打。我将戒指。我将……等一下，安静点。
No, no, I'll ring. I'll ring. I'll...wait, while it's quieter.
爸爸。这是公牛。
Dad. It's nowt.
这是……这是压力。
It's... It's stress.
昨晚，我压力很大。
Last night, it was stressful.
我很好。我是。
I'm fine. I am.
我从来没有这么快乐过!
I've never been happier!
他笑了笑，这比任何药都好。
HE CHUCKLES That's better than any medicine.
你昨晚没带药，对吧?
You didn't have your pills on you last night, did you?
不…但我现在已经拿走了。你什么时候才能学会?无论你走到哪里，你都得带着它们。
No...but I've taken them now. When will you learn? You've got to take them with you, wherever you go.
尤其是现在有这么多…恶作剧
Especially now with all of these... shenanigans
你已经开始进入……。好吧，我会的。
you've started getting into... Up to. Right, well, I will.
答应我。我保证。
Promise me. I promise.
过几天就会有个混蛋冒出来。你现在在打电话，
And bugger popping down in t'next few days. You're ringing now,
等大家都走了。好吧。
as soon as everyone's gone. All right.
不。对吗?
No. Right, as in...?
是的，正确就是正确。
Yes, right as in right.
抱歉打扰一下。
Sorry to interrupt.
我要下车了。我今天下午应该设法开始工作。
I'm going to get off. I ought to try and get into work this afternoon.
我来照顾他们，你自己照顾好自己。
I'll look after 'em. You take care of yourself.
是的，我会的。和你。
Yeah, I will. And you.
不要沮丧。
Don't be depressed.
这是浪费时间。
It's a waste of time.
继续前进。
Just move on.
我知道说起来容易做起来难。
It's easier said than done, I know.
祝你好运…是的,很好。我们将会看到。
Good luck with, um... Yeah, well. We'll see.
安全驾驶!
Drive safely!
我会把他送到学校。你能保持清醒吗?
I'll drop him off at school. Will you be able to stay awake?
谢谢你…Robbie。
Thank you...Robbie.
我给你洗个热水澡。哦!
I'm running you a nice, hot bath. Oh!
我给你放了一些泡泡进去。
I put you some bubbles in.
哦。你喜欢泡泡吗?
Aw. Do you like bubbles?
我喜欢泡泡。它会温暖你的。
I love bubbles. It'll warm you through.
它将。
It will.
嗯，我是说洗个热水澡——一般要半个小时才能洗满，
Well, I say a nice hot bath - it generally takes half an hour to fill,
到那时，天气会稍微凉爽一些，但是……
by which time, it's slightly cooler, but...
它会很可爱的。
It'll be lovely.
我们有很多毛巾。
And we've got plenty towels.
好。我把你们俩放到暖气片上了
Good. I've put you two over t'radiator
我在浴室旁边给你装了个小收音机。
and I've set you up a little radio next to t'bath.
我把它放到二台。
I'll put it on Radio 2.
你喜欢二台吗?
It is Radio 2 you like?
我爱二台!
I love Radio 2!
我再给你沏点茶好吗?
Can I make you some more tea?
不!我累坏了。
No! I'm all tea-ed out.
我给你煮一壶好咖啡!
I'll make you a nice pot of coffee!
然后你可以走出浴室，喝一杯热咖啡!
Then you can step out of the bath and have a cup of hot coffee!
你把我宠坏了。
You're spoiling me.
是的,嗯…
Yeah, well...
这是t 'plan。
that's t'plan.
所以你最好习惯它……
So you'd better get used to it...
Buttershaw夫人!
Mrs Buttershaw!
因为从现在开始，一切都将如此!
Because that's the way it's going to be from now on!
正确的。
Right.
嗨。
Hi.
嗨。你一定累坏了。
Hi. You must be exhausted.
你送孩子们上学了吗?
Did you send the boys to school?
不，他们都在电视机前睡着了。西莉亚怎么样?
No, they're both asleep in front of the telly. How's Celia?
好啊!
Fine!
有点——我不知道——摇晃。
A bit - I don't know - wobbly.
冲击,可能。
Shock, probably.
她想留在那里，所以…
She wanted to stay over there, so...
发生这种事很奇怪。
It's a weird thing to happen.
我给你煮点咖啡好吗?
Can I make you some coffee?
嗯…
Um...
不，谢谢。
No, thank you.
我要去睡一会儿，然后我可能…试着去工作。
I'm going to go to sleep for a bit, then I might...try and go into work.
今天肯定没人期待你来吧。
Oh, surely no-one's going to expect you in today.
我可以…吗?怎么啦？
Could I...? What?
我想说点什么，告诉你。
I wanted to say something, tell you something.
怎么啦？
What?
我讨厌我们之间出的问题。
I hate what's gone wrong between us.
我不知道你是否会原谅我，
I don't know if you're ever going to forgive me,
但我跟自己做了个约定再也不骗你了
but I made this deal with myself that I would never lie to you ever again.
或者以任何方式欺骗你，
Or deceive you in any way, shape or form,
希望有一天，你可能会……
in the hope that one day, you would possibly...
所以，我想让你知道，纯粹因为我觉得有责任，
So, I want you to know that purely because I felt responsible,
有罪，上帝知道……
guilty, God knows...
真替她难过，
sorry for her,
因为她太…可怜，我借给了
because she's so...pathetic, I lent -
我给了朱蒂丝一些房租钱。
gave - Judith some money for her rent.
什么时候? !今天早上，但我跟她说得很清楚了那东西是哪里来的。
When?! This morning, but I've made it clear to her there's no more where that came from.
而且——而且——我告诉过她我会把一切都告诉你的。
And - and - I've told her that I'd be telling you all about it.
她打电话来求我，
She rang up begging,
乞讨!
begging!
她几乎没有……把握生活的现实。
She's got almost no... grasp on the realities of life.
哇哇哇。可怜的贱人。
Aww. Poor bitch.
我希望她不存在。
I wish she didn't exist.
这样说别人是很糟糕的。
Which is a terrible thing to say about someone.
我一直在想。是吗?
I've been thinking. Yeah?
这在这里行得通。为了孩子们，我们可以礼貌点，不是吗?
This can work here. We can be civil, can't we, for the boys?
就像你说的，每个人都有空间。
And like you said, there's room for everyone.
确定。所以呢?
Sure. So?
我有男朋友了。
I'm seeing someone.
Y-Y-Y……嗯。
Y-Y-Y... Mmm.
你是谁?嗯。
You are? Mmm.
你吗?谁?
You? Who?
什么时候?这不是……
When? It's not...
我不知道这是不是我想要的，但是…
I don't know if it's what I want entirely yet, but...
我不试试就不知道。
I won't know if I don't try.
谁?
Who?
一个人。谁? !
Someone. Who?!
没关系!对我很重要!
It doesn't matter! Matters to me!
我不会告诉你是谁的，约翰，所以…她吹覆盆子
I'm not going to tell you who it is, John, so... SHE BLOWS RASPBERRY
工作上的人?可能。可能不是。
Someone at work? Possibly. Possibly not.
它是!你可能会这么想。
It is! You may think that.
我无法发表评论。
I couldn't possibly comment.
谁?我要去睡觉了。
Who? I'm going to bed.
谁? !约翰!谁? !这就是交易!
Who?! John! Who?! That's the deal!
等等，我又不是和你住在一个屋檐下
Hang on, I'm not living under the same roof as you
当你和别人在一起的时候!
while you're having it off with someone else!
你知道门在哪里。
Well, you know where the door is.
你在撒谎吗，卡罗琳?你在撒谎吗?!
Are you lying, Caroline? Are you lying?!
我不说谎!那是谁?!
I don't do lies! Well, who is it then?!
没有人!为什么这是秘密?!
No-one! Why's it a secret?!
因为我不想听你的任何意见
Because I don't want to have to listen to any of your opinions
还有评论和愚蠢的垃圾。
and comments and inane bloody rubbish.
所以是我认识的人!
So it's someone I know!
也许，也许不是!
Maybe, maybe not!
怎么回事?!什么都没有。
What's going on?! Nothing.
嗨,孩子们!
Hi, kids!
怎么了?
DOOR SLAMS What's up?
她的……怎么啦？
She's... What?
看到一个人。
Seeing someone.
妈妈?是的。
Mum? Yes.
妈妈? !是的!
Mum?! Yes!
谁?一些……我不知道!
Who? Some... I don't know!
她在学校里有和什么特别的人在一起吗?
Does she bother with anyone in particular at school?
不。别傻了!
No. Don't be stupid!
卡洛琳!
Caroline!
他敲门，卡洛琳!
HE KNOCKS ON DOOR Caroline!
来吧!开门!
Come on! Open the door!
你去哪儿了?我哪里没说过?你不能把他搬进来。
Where've you been? Where haven't I? You're not moving him in here.
我很高兴我们……谈过了。
I'm glad we...talked.
你想什么时候出去吃顿饭吗?
Do you fancy going out for a meal some time?
继续冒险!全体:我们在Soyland!
Keep having adventures! ALL: We're up Soyland!
我被利用了。
I've been used.
朱迪思?是的。注意你在哪里……
Judith? Yeah. Mind where you're...
．.打到他的后牙。你不能把他留在这里!
..to the back teeth of him. You're not leaving him here!
他陷入困境都是你的错。
It's your fault he's in this mess.
嘿!那么你还没死。
Hey! You're not dead, then.
你想过找伴郎吗?我从来没当过伴郎。
Have you thought about a best man? I've never been a best man.
哦，我不知道约翰在哪里。
Oh, I haven't a clue where John is.
西莉亚!哦,上帝!发生了什么事? !
Celia! Oh, God! What's happened?!
字幕:红蜂传媒有限公司
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd